Good Morning, Church!
Hallelujah!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Viewers at home, wherever you are, we salute your faith.
Thank You, Lord!
We continue to move according to the Spirit of God wave.
When He waves this direction, we follow; that direction, we follow.
That is the message you are receiving every week.
Like the issue of Holy Spirit - the Spirit of Father.
Hallelujah!
KNOWING JESUS, KNOWING THE HOLY SPIRIT
If you don't know the Holy Spirit, you cannot know Jesus.
I know Jesus; I know the Holy Spirit.
This is the issue we are going to talk about today.
Our title:
KNOWING JESUS, KNOWING THE HOLY SPIRIT
Let someone say:
If you say you know Jesus without knowing the Holy Spirit,
that is not Jesus in the power of the Holy Ghost.
He is a Spirit and His worshippers must do so in spirit and truth.
What kind of Jesus are we talking about?
KNOWING JESUS, KNOWING THE HOLY SPIRIT
Hallelujah!
We take our text from various books:
1 Corinthians 2:1-end.
John 16 - you can take your reading from the beginning.
John 3:27 -
it will give you some clue of what we are about to talk about today.
2 Corinthians 5:7 - about faith.
2 Corinthians 4:18 - that one too will help you.
Thank you.
Let's take our reading from the book of 1 Corinthians 2.
"And so it was with me, brothers and sisters. When I came to you,
I did not come with eloquence or human wisdom as I proclaimed to you the testimony about God."
Verse 2.
"For I resolved to know nothing while I was with you except Jesus Christ and him crucified."
Verse 3.
"I came to you in weakness with great fear and trembling.
My message and my preaching were not with wise and persuasive words,
but with a demonstration of the Spirit's power,"
Verse 5.
"so that your faith might not rest on human wisdom, but on God's power."
Hallelujah.
When you now go down, you will find God's wisdom revealed by the Spirit.
This is verse 6.
"We do, however, speak a message of wisdom among the mature,
but not the wisom of this age or of the rulers of this age..."
Take your time to read to the end.
Many other books have been given to you.
Hallelujah.
Taking your reading from verse 1 to the end of 1 Corinthians 2,
you will find that the Spirit is the organ by which we apprehend divine things;
man's spirit is dead because of sin.
The natural man - that is, the man of mind and the intellect - cannot understand
nor receive things of the Spirit.
Where there is no vision, people perish.
And this is what is going on now; this is what is happening in our generation.
Things perish.
You cannot see satan in the natural.
I do not see satan in the natural; I see satan on the other side - spirit world.
This is why there is no vision - perish, destruction, killing.
Tell your neighbour:
I do not see satan in the natural; I see satan on the other side - the spirit world.
That is why the Bible says where there is no vision, people perish.
satan ...
Tell your neighbour:
Where is no vision - perish.
What can you see here?
It is impossible to see what is here with your sight.
With your sight, it is impossible to see what is here.
Everyone is exposed to things that are not consistent with God's Word.
If these things control your feelings and your feelings control your faith,
you can be a Christian yet controlled by satan's devices.
Tell your neighbour:
I do not see satan in the natural; I see satan on the other side - the spirit world.
Tell your neighbour again.
I do not see satan in the natural; I see satan on the other side - spirit world.
I am more comfortable walking in the Spirit because that is where I can hear Jesus.
Tell your neighbour:
- "T.B. Joshua!"
- "Yes, sir."
In the spirit.
But in the natural...
Can you see the life you live today?
I am more comfortable walking in the Spirit. That is where I can hear Jesus.
God gives us His Spirit to apprehend Him.
KNOWING JESUS, KNOWING THE HOLY SPIRIT
Don't forget.
There has been a great mix-up in the Church.
It is the erroneous assumption that spiritual truths can be intellectually perceived.
It is possible to grow up in the Church as a baby -
your father is founder of this, founder of that church -
and learn all rites but not know Jesus because Jesus is not known by those external things.
Jesus is not known by those external things.
In John 16, it is perfectly plain that the Holy Spirit is the One that reveals Jesus to us.
You can read your New Testament and still never find Jesus in it.
You can be convinced that Jesus is the Son of God and still never find Jesus.
You can be a publisher of the Bible.
You can know about Christ dying for you.
You can head this or that religious organisation.
You can be the Founder and General Overseer
and still never know Jesus of Nazareth in the power of the Holy Ghost.
In the Church, there are two Christs.
You need to know the one you are worshipping today.
There are two Christs:
1. The Christ of story and of history and song - the baby Jesus.
2. Then, there is this Christ which the Holy Spirit reveals.
Many people know about Christ but they don't know Christ.
There is a difference - knowing about Christ and knowing Christ.
John 3:27 - 'No man can receive except it is given from above'.
2 Timothy 3:16 - 'All Scripture is given by inspiration of God and is profitable'.
If you are reasoned into Christianity, some wise fellow can reason you out of it
unless you know the Holy Spirit.
KNOWING JESUS, KNOWING THE HOLY SPIRIT
If you are reasoned into Christianity without knowing the Holy Ghost -
and you become a Christian, claim you are a Christian without the Holy Ghost -
some wise fellow can reason you out of it - unless you know the Holy Spirit.
Knowing Jesus is knowing the Holy Ghost.
This is why you see people today, "I'm a member of this church" -
"Today, I don't want to go to church again".
"I used to be a Christian but no..."
"I'm this" - "No!"
"I'm a pastor" - "No, I'm no more"
"I'm an evangelist" - "No, I'm no more an evangelist"
Some wise fellow can reason you out if you are reasoned into Christianity.
Why? Because Christianity falls or stands on Christ Jesus,
stands or falls on the illumination of the Holy Ghost.
It is either the Holy Spirit or darkness.
It is either the Holy Ghost or darkness.
The Holy Ghost is God's imperative of life.
If our faith is to be a New Testament faith, if Jesus Christ is to be the Christ of God
rather than the Christ of history or story, the illumination of the Holy Ghost will tell our heart
that we are learning at Jesus' feet, not at man's feet.
Are you...
No, what I'm saying does not demand for applause.
It demands for crying.
Sober reflection because I don't see Christians among you.
I'm seeing religious people sitting down.
So why are you clapping?
I cannot see Christians among you.
I'm seeing religious people sitting down.
As it should be - the way your forefathers were having God,
the way your father is praying and fasting,
that is the way you are going about serving God.
The Christ of history, story, song - baby Jesus.
Who is a Christian among us?
If you are a Christian, can you tell me who is talking to you?
Are you seeing beyond me? - That is what you call Christian.
If you are a Christian, you live by the Holy Ghost; you would be able to see beyond me.
You can't see beyond me; you only see me talking to you.
That is all you see.
That is why you can go out when you decide to; you can do anything.
That is why tomorrow you may not come to church if you are not healed or blessed
because you are reasoned into Christianity.
If today is your last day, where are you going?
Is there any kingdom for religious (people)?
Thy Kingdom come; Thy will be done.
Where are you going if today is your last day?
You will tell Jesus, "Im a member of this church; I go to church" -
is that the excuse you want to give?
I can't see Christians among you.
We continue the journey.
This is the message God asked me to give you.
KNOWING JESUS, KNOWING THE HOLY SPIRIT
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you are not filled with the Spirit, you cannot obey the written Word.
That is the painful part.
You are just carrying the Bible and you are just reading the history part of it
because there is no way you can obey the Word of God if you are not filled.
That is the most painful part of it.
Where is your Bible?
See. This one - you cannot obey it.
You will just be reading it as a religious man.
You read to preach, teach it but to live it - it is not possible.
If you cannot obey the Scripture, you quench God.
You quench Him.
That is the most painful part.
Reading the Bible, carrying the Bible...
The Word here is not just history; the Holy Spirit carried the writers along.
That is the most painful thing - very, very painful.
Many of you have read this Bible four to five times.
We have many publishers here - publishers of the Bible.
They are among you that publish the Bible for daily bread.
Where are we going?
That is the most painful part of it.
The most painful part of it - I mean the Bible is irrelevant to you.
I will be stretching my hand now; you will see people shaking
but you don't know what is shaking them.
The resurrection power that flows within me to them -
you cannot see it but you always see people shaking and falling.
It becomes a magic to you.
"Ah! What is this? Without touching, what is making people to fall?"
You can't see because you are not filled.
Through that, it is blaspheming.
You will not say it out but your heart is saying a lot.
Your heart is saying a lot; your heart is blaspheming.
Your heart is not at rest.
You keep blaspheming; you keep seeing what you do not understand.
Your heart will blaspheme.
This is the problem we find ourselves in.
I will stand here to tell you, "Don't go to that church".
Why should I say that you should not go there?
If you go there, you will be able to see more.
Seeing more will help your history.
It will make you adequate in serving God.
If that church is not good, go there. See for yourself.
If you have not seen enough darkness, you cannot appreciate light.
That is it.
Please.
You are not serving God without the Holy Spirit.
If you are serving God without the Holy Spirit, you are serving a god you do not know.
Tell your neighbour:
If I serve God without the Holy Ghost, I am serving a god I do not know.
It is the Spirit that makes us know Him.
Serving God without the Holy Spirit is serving a god you do not know.
This is the god our forefathers served and this is the life you are living today.
Someone keeps telling you what God says.
Someone keeps telling you, "God says you should sleep".
That is the life you want to live throughout.
"God says you should sleep."
"God says you should wake up."
"God says you should fast."
"God says you should do this; God says you should go to London."
Is that the life you want to live throughout?
It means you are still serving a god you do not know.
Someone is telling you what God says.
It means you do not know that god; that is why someone is telling you.
For how long?
Very, very painful.
Tell your neighbour, "Very, very painful".
That is the way I see it.
Very, very ... painful.
Intellectually perceived.
Spiritual truth - we can intellectually perceive it.
Very, very painful - you have to get out of this.
Forget about your problem.
You don't have a problem; that is the only problem you have.
Every other problem is not a problem.
The greatest problem is for you to serve a god you do not know.
Tell your neighbour:
The greatest problem - all other are not problems.
The greatest problem is to serve a god you do not know.
Imagine your age today - how old are you?
You have been serving God...
You have a dream - you have to consult somebody to tell you the meaning.
You have a job - you want to know whether it is a good job.
You want to marry - you carry it medically to know whether it is good;
spiritually, you run from one place to another to know whether it is the right thing.
This is the life you have been living.
And such life is not profitable.
A man cannot receive except it is given from above.
But you keep receiving from people.
Where are we going?
You say you are poor; you are not poor.
You say you are sick; you are not sick.
You are only serving a god you do not know.
If you are blessed today and you still continue serving a god you do not know,
you will still come back poorer - unless you serve God you know.
TT: Mel Flowers 30/10/2018
RV ROBERT BEGIER 02/11/2018